Abhinav Gupta

Digital Product Designer

www.itsabhi.com abhinav191@gmail.com +44-07385965473

www.linkedin.com/in/abhinav191

A multi-disciplinary engineer turned designer with 5+ years of domain experience in designing and developing for enterprise and consumer grade applications to create meaningful and easy to use products.

Self motivated with keen interest in making simple, clean and clear designs. Always on a look-out for new technologies and trends.

Work Experience

Google - Interaction Designer

MAY 2022 - PRESENT, LONDON-UK

Working on a dev-ops tool to help Google release applications like Gmail, Youtube more efficiently with a simple, intuitive experience.

VMware - Product Designer III

NOVEMBER 2019 - MAY 2022, BANGALORE-INDIA

Helping shape up experiences for the flagship product VMware vRealize Automation – a powerful and easy-to-use Infrastructure Automation Platform. Currently the only designer from India for the team driving forward the initiative for providing a consumer grade experience to our users.

SAP - UX Designer

JULY 2017 - OCTOBER 2019, BANGALORE-INDIA

Worked as the Lead Designer from Bangalore-India location to create unified experiences for the internal tools development team. Extensive collaboration with Design teams, Product Managers and Developers from global locations for user research, testing, design reviews and driving local and global projects forward.

Group10 Tech. - Sr. Software Engineer

OCTOBER 2012 - JUNE 2015, GURGAON-INDIA

Worked with front-end technologies like HTML,CSS and Javascript and frameworks like Drupal with mobile platform development in Android to design websites and mobile applications for the clients providing an easy to use and simple user experience and defining and streamlining the design process of making applications.

Education

National Institute of Design

MASTER OF DESIGN (M.DES)
INFORMATION DESIGN
2015–2017, BANGALORE-INDIA

Indraprastha University

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY (B.TECH)
INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY
2008-2012, DELHI

Skills

Design: UX Design, Interaction Design, User Research, Usability Testing, UI Design, Information Architecture, Motion Design, Graphic Design, Data Visualisation

Tools: Figma, Sketch, Framer, Principle, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe After Effects, Adobe InDesign

Technology: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, Bulma, Git